{"data":[{"question":"I sat near the window whenever I ________ a bus.","a":"take","b":"took","c":"has taken","d":"had taken","answer":"2","explain":"\n- When the main clause is in past tense, in the subordinate clause the past tense shows another completed action related in time to the main action.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"It was raining hard when I ________ there.","a":"get","b":"got","c":"has got","d":"had got","answer":"2","explain":"\n- When + Simple past tense, simple past continuous.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"She ________ the piano since she was a child.","a":"plays","b":"played","c":"has played","d":"had played","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Present Perfect: \n+ Express action happened at an unspecified time before now. The exact time is not important.\u00a0\n+ Unspecific expressions: since, never, once, many times, several times, before, so far,yet, just, for.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"The sun ________ in the east.","a":"rise","b":"rose","c":"rises","d":"has risen","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Simple present tense: expresses event that is always true.\u00a0\n- Subject (the sun) is singular.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"How long do you want me to heat the oil? Heat it till it ________ to smoke.","a":"begins","b":"began","c":"has begun","d":"had begun","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Future present tense\/simple present tense until\/till \/when\/as soon as\/ before + simple present tense.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"How long are you going to stay here? - I'm going to stay here till my brother ________ his exams.","a":"finishes","b":"finished","c":"would finish","d":"will finish","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Future present tense\/simple present tense until\/till \/when\/as soon as\/ before + simple present tense.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"When will you start the trip? - We'll leave as soon as we ________ our tickets.","a":"get","b":"got","c":"will get","d":"would get","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Future present tense\/simple present tense until\/till \/when\/as soon as\/ before + simple present tense.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"I'm learning English. Well, when we ________ English fluently, we may find a good job.","a":"speak","b":"spoke","c":"has spoken","d":"will speak","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Simple present tense\/future tense + while\/when + simple present tense.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"By the time you ________ this book, your meal will get cold. - Oh, I only have a few pages left.","a":"read","b":"will read","c":"have read","d":"had read","answer":"3","explain":"\n- By the time\/when + present perfect, simple future tense.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"Are you taking English courses? - Yes, and my teacher says that when I ________ five courses, I shall be able to speak it quite fluently.","a":"have taken","b":"took","c":"has taken","d":"will take","answer":"1","explain":"\n- By the time\/when + present perfect, simple future tense.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"18","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"}]}